Oh, will my torment never end?
唉 苦日子何时是个头儿啊？
First, I had to vie for Megatron's favor against that treacherous harpy, Airachnid.
从前要与那只奸诈的鹰身女妖毒蜘蛛 争讨威震天的欢心
Now I must contend with Shockwave and his incorrigible beast!
现在 震荡波和他那些无可救药的野兽又来跟我争宠
Oh, look on the bright side, Starscream.
噢 想想好的一面嘛 红蜘蛛
At least one of them is currently on ice,
至少其中一个已经冻成了雕像
locked up tight in the vault of our warship.
严严实实地锁在战舰的保险库里
How I would love to stuff Shockwave and his mangy abomination right into that stasis pod beside her!
我真想把震荡波和他那些 可恨的癞皮狗也塞进静止舱里！
The only reason his "Project Predacon" is currently in full swing
他的巨狰狞计划之所以能够顺风顺水
is because I supervised the acquisition of his dozens of Predacon bones.
全靠本座帮他找回了那几十具巨狰狞骸骨
Will you please keep your lab rat quiet
在我发牢骚的时候
while I'm airing my grievances?
能不能让你的小白鼠别哼哼了？
Starscream, help me!
红蜘蛛…救救我…
My, my, my... Whatever have you been inflicting upon poor Cylas?
哎呀呀 你都对可怜的塞拉斯做了什么啊？
Ha! Well anything that merits the need for a living petri dish.
哈 都是些活体培养皿该干的事
Despite your justifiable lack of regard for his human side,
你不顾及里面人类的死活倒也罢了
It doesn't trouble you to watch what remains of your former partner endure your scientific endeavors?
但看着你前搭档的残体受尽折磨 你于心何忍？
Not really. Besides, Cylas once had poor Breakdown pinned to his lab table.
没啥感觉 此外 塞拉斯也曾把打击绑在他的试验台上
I think my former partner would be pleased to be a part.
我想我的前搭档会很乐意享受其中的
What just happened?
怎么回事？
You recall that synthetic energon I recovered from the Autobots?
记得我从汽车人那里还原的人造能量吗？
Well, I've been reproducing the formula to test its viability as an alternative energy source.
我按照配方复制了一些 以测试它作为替代能源的效果
However, the compound remains erratic, and there have been side effects.
不过 这种化合物很不稳定 而且明显带有副作用
Such as?
比方说？
Starscream, I hope you replaced your t-cog.
红蜘蛛 希望你换过变形齿轮
Because I'm going to tear it out all over again and feed it to knock out!
因为我会再把它扯出来 塞进击倒的臭嘴里！
Sheer unbridled aggression.
产生不受控制的攻击性
Such power and fury!
瞧瞧这力量 这怒火！
Megatron has long desired a beast machine super soldier.
威震天不是一直想要个超级野兽机器战士嘛
And we now possess the means of delivering one to him.
看来我们能为他供货了
Tell me of the Predacon protoforms.
跟我说说那些巨狰狞原生体
What is the status of their incubation?
它们的孵化进度如何？
Mm-hm. Uh-huh...
嗯 嗯…
Master, if I do say so myself,
主人 我可不是往自己脸上贴金
I have made the most intriguing discovery. It appears that--
我有了一个迷人的发现 它看起来…
Not now!
别来烦我！
Please continue, Shockwave.
请继续 震荡波
No, no one important.
不…不是什么重要角色
Did you speak with our liege about our little enterprise?
你和我们的君王说了吗？关于我们的那个小计划？
He was otherwise engaged.
他正忙别的事呢
I am going to make you suffer in ways you will not believe!
我会用你们想象不到的手段 折磨死你们！
Just how much of this synth-en have you given him?
你给他注射了多少合成能量？
Two additional doses, three at the most.
又打了两针 顶多三针
But Cylas' increasingly volatile nature isn't the only wrinkle.
不过 塞拉斯越来越不稳定的状态 还不是唯一的问题
It appears that the more green stuff I administer,
似乎这种绿玩意 我给他注射得越多
the faster this monstrosity formerly known as Breakdown burns through his own natural energon reserves.
这只由打击变成的怪物 体内原本的能量就消耗得越快
This will not do!
那怎么行！
Megatron already possesses one unruly beast with that Predacon of his!
威震天已经有巨狰狞那种狂暴的野兽了
What good is another freak of nature that cannot be controlled?
再给他一只无法控制的怪物能有什么…
Wait. I'm a fool...
等等… 我傻了不是？
Dark Energon!?
黑暗能量？！
You are more than a fool, Starscream.
你不是傻 红蜘蛛！
I think your neural cluster has blown a massive fuse!
我看你是大脑短路了！
Oh, on the contrary, dear doctor.
噢 恰恰相反 我亲爱的医生
Adding Dark Energon to the formula should provide Lord Megatron with full control over his super-soldier.
将黑暗能量加入配方 能让威震天陛下完全控制他的超级战士
Okay, true that Lord Megatron seems to possess a symbiotic link to anyone or thing infused with the dark matter,
没错 威震天陛下确实与注射了 黑暗能量的人或物体有某种共生联系
allowing him to manipulate them as if they were puppets.
借此他可以像操纵木偶一样控制他们
But... have you forgotten what the so-called Blood of Unicron did to our warship!?
但是 难道你忘了这所谓的“宇宙大帝之血” 对我们的战舰做了什么吗？
That was the result of a massive infusion.
那是因为注射量过大
I am suggesting a drop or two, merely enough to allow our master to command his warrior at will.
我建议加一两滴 刚好可以让 我们的主人随心所欲地控制他的战士
Even so, it's too drastic a measure to undertake without Shockwave's approval.
即便如此 没经过震荡波的批准就这么干 太冒险了！
I do, after all, report to him.
毕竟我现在归他管
Not on this project!
这个项目与他无关！
Super soldiers fall under military operations,
超级战士项目属于军事行动
Meaning, dear knock out, that you now report to me.
也就是说 亲爱的击倒 你现在归我管
Are we clear?
明白了么？
Wait for it.
等着看好戏吧
Ugh. Humans in any form cannot be relied upon.
啊 人类在任何形态都一无是处！
It's alive!
它活过来了！
Scrap.
糟了！
Oh, for the love of-- Now what?
啊！看在老天爷的份上！又怎么了？
I tried to tell you before.
我早就告诉你了
It's a side effect of the synth-en. He's burned through his own natural reserves.
这是合成能量的副作用 他耗光了自身原本的能量
Then perhaps we should withhold any infusions for a while.
那或许我们该把注射的事先缓缓
Might calm Cylas down a bit.
也许这样能让塞拉斯冷静下来
Make him a tad more manageable.
让他更听话一些
Need... energon.
需要…能量…
Ah! Do you think he's actually trying to...
啊 你觉得他真的想…
Suck out our energon with that thing?
用那玩意把我们的能量吸干？
Sure seems that way.
看起来是这么回事！
Ah! Ah! Ah!...
啊！啊！啊！
See if you can hold him off!
试试看你能不能拖住他！
You! What?
啥？
Wait for me!
带上我！
We need to sound the alarm!
我们必须…拉响警报！
Out of the question! Megatron will undoubtedly hold us responsible.
绝对不行！威震天一定会认为这是我们的错！
But... we are.
可这…本来就是啊！
Well, you are, mostly.
其实 大部分是你的错！
Anyway, his lordship doesn't need to know that.
无论如何 陛下没必要知道这些！
Not if we handle this the right way.
只要我们能摆平这个烂摊子
Meaning?
怎么摆平？
Use your head, Knock out.
动动脑子 击倒！
This ship is crawling with highly trained Vehicon troopers, armed for combat.
这艘船满是训练有素的士兵 个个装备精良
The moment Cylas attempts to feed, they will neutralize him for us.
一旦塞拉斯想吸食他们 他们会帮我们干掉他
Problem solved.
问题也就迎刃而解了
Aah!...
啊！
Once we recover Cylas' body, We must dispose of it as quickly and efficiently as possible.
一旦我们找回塞拉斯的尸体 必须赶紧毁尸灭迹！
No trace of him can be allowed to remain.
不能留下一块碎片！
His... Infected body...
他那被感…感…感染的尸体
- Ah!? - Aah!
- 啊！ - 哇啊！
Gone. Completely drained of energon.
死了 能量被完全吸干了
Tell me something, starscream.
跟我说说 红蜘蛛
When you said "problem solved," is this even close to what you had in mind?
当你说“问题迎刃而解”时 你考虑到这种情况了么？
I do not appreciate your tone, knock out!
注意你的语气 击倒！
This brewing catastrophe is hardly my fault.
这场祸可不是我惹出来的！
Well, it certainly isn't mine!
那肯定也不是我惹出来的！
Oh, no? You're the mastermind who chose to experiment with synthetic Energon.
不是？是你自作聪明 拿人造能量做实验的！
And you're the monkey wrench who thought it was a good idea to dabble in voodoo!
是你怂恿我往里面加料的！
Energon.
能量…
- Ah!
- 啊！ - 哇啊！
I thought you said he had no spark?
你不是说他的火种都没了么？
Dark energon, it re-animates the dead!
是黑暗能量 它能使死者复生！
Aim for the head!
打它的头！
What? How do you know?
啥？你怎么知道？
I have seen human horror films!
我看过人类的恐怖电影
At drive-in theatres!
在汽车影院！
Ah! Forget the head. Go for the spark!
啊！打头没用 瞄准他的火种！
We severed its link to the dark energon.
我们切断了他汲取黑暗能量的通道
Human horror films, waste of time.
看人类的恐怖电影完全是浪费时间！
Energon...
能量…
If the mutation can be passed along with a single bite, The entire crew is at risk.
如果被咬一口就会感染变异 那么全体船员都有危险！
Heh!? You're saying Cylas could beget more Terrorcons?
怎么着？你是说塞拉斯会弄出更多的僵尸来？
Mm, could happen.
极有可能
And the ensuing feeding frenzy could turn this entire warship into a scrap heap.
而随之而来的再扩散 会把整艘飞船变成一个废铁场！
So now can we sound the alarm?
所以 我现在能拉响警报了吧？
You, there... have you noticed any unusual activity...
你们几个！有没有在这个区域发现什么…
in... this... sector?
…不寻常的情况？
- Ah! - Ah...!
我的个娘呀！
- Aah! - Let's go!
啊！啊！
In here!
快进去！
Knockout, this situation might be a bit more dire than either of us ever imagined.
击倒 眼前的情况可能比我们想象的要恐怖得多
Mm. I find it rather ironic that after battling Autobots all these years,
嗯 真是讽刺 和汽车人火拼了这么多年
getting smacked down... shot at... blown up...
被砸晕…被击中…被炸飞…
This is how our lights go out.
到头来却摊上了这么个死法
Drained of our precious fluids.
被吸干宝贵的能量而死…
If this is indeed the end, If we are to become Terrorcon chow,
如果今天真是我们的末日 如果我们真要成为僵尸的口粮
It has been an honor serving Lord Megatron with you...
我想说 很荣幸能和你一起为威震天陛下尽忠…
You're no Breakdown. Though I must confess... I have always admired your lustrous finish.
虽然你不像打击那么阳刚 但我得承认我一直很欣赏你那光鲜的涂装
Well, then...
咳咳 那么…
We should be going.
该出去了
Ah!
啊！
Would either of you like to tell me what exactly is going on?!
你们两个谁能告诉我 到底发生什么事了？
Y-yes. Absolutely nothing, my liege.
呃…当然是…啥事都没发生 我的君王
All is quiet... too quiet. One could even say "dull."
一切都很正常 太正常了 几乎可以说是无聊了
Funny... because the Dark Energon within my spark has been pulsing.
是嘛 那为什么我火种内的黑暗能量正蠢蠢欲动？
Allow me to handle this.
还是让我来处理吧
It's Knockout's fault!
这都是击倒的错！
Precisely my... What?!
完全正确…啥？！
He infused Cylas with a cocktail comprised of Dark and synthetic Energon,
他调了一杯“黑暗”加“人造”能量鸡尾酒 给塞拉斯打进去了
creating a monstrous mutation, which is now on the verge of turning your entire crew into mindless Energon-sucking Terrorcons!
制造出了一个变异怪物 现在它会把整船人变成吸食能量的僵尸
I do not know from what madness your yarn springs, Starscream.
我不知道你鬼话连篇地又在抽什么疯 红蜘蛛
but if I learn that you have been dabbling with my Dark Energon stores again,
但要是再让我发现 你乱动我的黑暗能量
attempting to infuse yourself with its formidable power...
并试图给自己注射这种强大的力量
Uh, my liege?
呃 我的君王…
let me just say, you have been awarded more chances for redemption than anyone in Decepticon history!
这么说吧 你得到的宽恕 已经比历史上任何一个霸天虎都多了！
Energon...
能量…
Hey, you there. What are you doing?
嘿！你！你在干什么！
I order you... stand down!
我命令你 退下！
We did try to tell you.
我们刚才就想告诉您来着
Mm-hmm.
没错
Then why can I not command the monster to follow my bidding?
那为什么我无法让那些怪物服从我的命令？
While the trace of Dark Energon should have granted you control over these ghouls,
黑暗能量本应让您能控制这些食尸鬼的
I believe the synthetic component may be corrupting your link to them.
我觉得或许是合成能量破坏了您和他们之间的联系
Initiate high alert.
启动紧急警报
Instruct all troops to keep their distance from the mutations and terminate on sight.
命令全体士兵与变异者保持距离 并对其格杀勿论！
Your fate, however, remains to be seen.
但你们俩的死活还要看接下来的表现
Why are you still here?!
还傻站在这里干什么？！
Find this creation of yours and eradicate it... immediately!
去找到你们创造的鬼东西 然后立即给我把它灭了！
I realize lord Megatron's only doing this to punish us,
我知道威震天陛下让我们干这个是为了惩罚我们
but how are we the best choice to hunt down Cylas?
但我们不是猎杀塞拉斯的合适人选啊
I mean, why not deploy his beloved beast-machine supersoldier,
我是说 为啥不派出他心爱的超级野兽机器战士？
After all, it is supposed to be the ultimate hunter.
毕竟他们才是什么终极猎人嘛
Out of the question.
绝对不行！
Can you imagine if the Predacon became infected?
如果巨狰狞被感染了 你能想象到那个情景吗？
Nothing could stop it.
那就没什么能阻挡它了
Energon.
能量…
Ah!
噢
Breakdown?
打击？
Did I not exterminate you once already?
我上次不是把你干掉了么？
Energon!
…能量…
Second time's the charm. Heh!
事不过二 哼！
But to be certain... I shall remove your very spark.
不过 保险起见…我要把你的火种挖出来！
Ah?! Cylas?
啊？！塞拉斯？
What ever have they done to you?
他们对你做了什么？
Ah, but more importantly, thank you for freeing me.
更重要的是 谢谢你放我出来
No. Thank... you...
不 谢谢你
Whatever.
随你怎么说
Insecticons, heed me.
机器昆虫们 听我号令
Heed me. Heed me.
…听我号令…
Your Queen has returned.
刀锋女王归来了
Our ordeal is finally over!
咱们的噩梦终于结束了
Or not.
或者刚刚开始
Scrap!
见鬼了！
Starscream! Have you made contact with the plague bringer?
红蜘蛛！你找到瘟疫的源头了吗？
Actually, my liege, I have good news.
事实上 我的君王 有个好消息
And... bad news.
还有个坏消息
Loyal servants, the time is now.
忠实的奴仆们 时机已经到来
Lay waste to all Decepticons!
消灭所有霸天虎！
Leave no trace of them in your wake!
让他们尸骨无存！
Soundwave!
声波！
I vow that on this day, the world will hear the sound of your screams!
我在此立誓 我要让全世界都听到你的哀嚎！
Ha!
上！
Nooo!
不！
Yes. The containment protocol you recommended to prevent any further outbreak is now under way.
是的 根据你的建议 阻止传染扩散的程序已开始实施
Oh, and, Shockwave, having just lost more than half our military might,
此外 震荡波 鉴于这次事件让我们损失过半
I cannot stress enough the importance of Project Predacon.
你的巨狰狞计划就变得至关重要
See if you can... speed things along, will you?
试一试能否加速其进程 好吗？
Knockout, need I remind you that, as the ship's medic,
击倒 我要提醒你 作为船上的医疗官
you report directly to Shockwave, not Starscream.
你的上级是震荡波 不是红蜘蛛
Understood, Master.
明白了 主人
Just to be sure, you will hand over all of your projects to him immediately,
保险起见 即刻将你手上的所有项目移交给震荡波
including this synthetic Energon.
包括人造能量项目
As you wish, my liege.
如您所愿 我的君王
And as for you...
至于你嘛…
Lord Megatron, if you will just allow me to explain things...
威震天陛下 请容小人解释一下…
No. Allow me to explain things...
不 还是让我解释一下
in a manner which I know you'll understand.
用一种你能听懂的方式
Your Majesty, we await your command.
女王陛下 我们期待着您的命令
Approach me. Serve your Queen.
过来 侍奉你的女王